Guide to the Alpha Phi Omega, Zeta Chapter, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alpha Phi Omega, Zeta Chapter, records
1948-2005
SC0867
Alpha Phi Omega. Zeta Chapter.
7.5 Linear feet
Records include minutes, correspondence, publications, clippings, photographs, publicity, and rosters, some of which are arranged in scrapbooks. Also included is a guest book from their 1983 anniversary and several videos (VHS).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Zeta Chapter of Alpha Phi Omega, a national community service fraternity, was chartered at Stanford on May 19, 1928. It was a men's fraternity until 1973 when Stanford admitted its first female member; admission of women became the national policy in 1976. Recent activities have included participating in an Earth Day cleanup at Muir Woods, serving soup kitchens, organizing the Trick-or-Treat canned food drive, and helping build children's playgrounds.
Description of the Collection
Records include minutes, correspondence, publications, clippings, photographs, publicity, and rosters, some of which are arranged in scrapbooks. Also included is a guest book from their 1983 anniversary and several videos (VHS).
Access Terms
Alpha Phi Omega. Zeta Chapter.; Student service--California.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accesion ARCH-2007-124
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs [cutting down trees and building structure], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs [color negs only], 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs [Fall sectionals], 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs, no date (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs (1 of 2) undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega photographs (2 of 2) undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Phi Omega slides, 1976-78 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alpha Phi Omega slides, no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Various materials [correspondence, publications, reports, newsletters, rosters, etc.], 1968-79 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Various materials, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Various materials, 1985-90 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, executive committee and chapter meetings, 1948-59 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks:
    - Winter 1953-Fall 1959 (contents: photos, newspaper clippings, correspondences, meeting agendas, Rosters) (Box 3)
    - Fall 1959-Fall 1963 (contents: photos, newspaper clippings, correspondences, publications, event publicity) (Box 3)
    - Fall 1970-Spring 1976 (contents: events '70-'76, annual special projects, member profiles '75-‘76) (Box 3)
    - 1976-Fall 1983 (contents: photos of members and events, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, correspondences) (Box 3)
    - Fall 1984-Spring 1985 (contents: APO Event Photos) (Box 3)
    - Summer 1985-Spring 1987 (contents: correspondences, meeting announcements, event photos, membership rosters) (Box 4)
    - Spring 1987-Spring 1990 (contents: APO Event Photos) (Box 4)
    - Fall 1989-Spring 1991 (contents: info on APO, event photos, membership rosters) (Box 4)
    - 1991-1993 (contents: event photos, rosters, correspondences) (Box 4)
    - 1993-1994 (contents: event photos) (Box 5)
    - 1994-1995 (contents: event photos and information, publications) (Box 5)
    - 1995-1996 (contents: event photos, publications) (Box 5)
  - Guestbook:
    - 1983 Anniversary (Box 5)
  - Photo Album:
    - 1999-2000 (Box 5)
  - VHS Tapes:
    - "APO Fall Sectionals 1999" 10/23/99 (Box 6)
    - "Earle M. Herbert video as Fall '93 namesake" (Box 6)
    - "Final Version" (Box 6)
  - Fall 1957-58 Pledge Class (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Membership Roster 1960-64 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of Torch and Trefoil 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Member Forms Classification (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Forms Aut & and before (mostly pledge tests) 1958-60 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Chapter Program 1957-8 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - National Bulletins 1955-59 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gamma Beta – San Jose State, correspondence, 1950-58 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Past Presidents on 30th anniversary 1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Advisors, correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Spring 1958 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Relating to Pledging 1955-57 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Thirteenth National Convention 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Administrative, 1962-64 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Inter-chapter Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Duplicate Forms – Nineteenth Sectional Conference (Stanford) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous from National Office 1957-58 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Twenty-First Sectional Conference (Cal) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fifteenth National Convention ('58) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Fourteenth National Convention (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Fall 1958 Pledge Class (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Pre-Registration Projects (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Conferences and Administrative 1950-73 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Keep Campus Clean" Campaign 1957-61 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 19th Sectional Conference – April 1958 (1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 19th Sectional Conference – April 1958 (2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 19th Sectional Conference – April 1958 (3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Current Membership Folder 1956-59 (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Current Membership Folder 1956-59 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Perm. File (assorted memos, correspondence) 1958-60 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Alpha Phi Omega #1 [5 pages describing the campus] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Financial records 1986-91 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1950-57 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1957-59 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1960-69 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1970-78 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1981-89 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Torch and Trefoil 1990-2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)